<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Coffee Comrade</title>
    <link>http://coffeecomrade.com</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <webMaster>bryanwarren@gmail.com (Bryan Matthew Warren)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>2011-03-01T18:39:09-05:00</pubDate>
    <copyright>Copyright 2011</copyright>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <description>Coffee reviews, tasting notes and commentary</description>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasting Notes - Dynamite Roasting - Black Powder Espresso Blend</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-dynamite-roasting-black-powder-espresso-blend.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue Mar 01 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-dynamite-roasting-black-powder-espresso-blend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.dynamiteroasting.com/'&gt;Dynamite Roasting&lt;/a&gt; is a local organic roaster in Black Mountain, NC. I&amp;#8217;ve written before about their Sumatra Mandheling roast–one of my favorite coffees. I recently had the chance to visit their coffee bar and pick up their &lt;a href='http://www.dynamiteroasting.com/onlinestore.html'&gt;Black Powder Espresso Blend&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dark roast has an intense coffee aroma with tones of cream and nut oil. As an espresso blend, the beans are roasted well into the second crack but don&amp;#8217;t suffer the common &amp;#8220;roasted-to-hell&amp;#8221; trait of many similar blends. There&amp;#8217;s no musky or meaty&lt;sup id='fnref:1'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:1' rel='footnote'&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; burnt smell here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flavor profile is extremely complex. Most pronounced is a smack of dark cocoa trailed by mild berry fruit notes and a hint of nut. The flavor is quite strong and rather dark, but remains balanced with no overwhelming elements. The finished cup has great body and a very smooth finish with fairly low acidity. Its flavor lingers and has a bit of bite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there&amp;#8217;s the gorgeous copper crema. Heaps of the stuff. It&amp;#8217;s like pouring a pint of Guinness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While at Dynamite&amp;#8217;s bar, I sampled a straight double shot and a double Americano. On a return trip, I tried another double Americano, but iced. Since then, I&amp;#8217;ve been enjoying double Americanos at home from my AeroPress. This blend holds up. I can see it working well in any blended coffee drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dynamite Roasting&amp;#8217;s Black Powder Espresso is–quite possibly–the best &lt;em&gt;espresso&lt;/em&gt; blend I&amp;#8217;ve ever had. It&amp;#8217;s complex but balanced; both subtle and bold. As good as it is, I wouldn&amp;#8217;t want it every day since it&amp;#8217;s so bold. A solid 4 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='footnotes'&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id='fn:1'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, over-roasted beans smell like meat. Baconesque, but in a bad way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='#fnref:1' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/review">review</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/tasting-notes">tasting-notes</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/espresso">espresso</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/dynamite">dynamite</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/4-stars">4-stars</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demanding Price</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/demanding-price.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat Feb 26 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/demanding-price/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The International Coffee Organization&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href='http://www.ico.org/news/cmr-0111-e.pdf'&gt;latest monthly report (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; is out and the news is still somewhat grim. They cite continued weather woes as the chief cause of low crop yields. Green coffee prices haven&amp;#8217;t been so high in over 15 years, and we&amp;#8217;ve seen a 55% increase in the past twelve months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chinese demand for coffee &lt;a href='http://www.bloomberg.com/apps/news?pid=newsarchive&amp;amp;sid=aq3ewkyLbKuc'&gt;grows about 20% annually&lt;/a&gt;, and India&amp;#8217;s market &lt;a href='http://www.businessweek.com/news/2010-04-28/coffee-demand-in-india-to-drive-imports-board-s-rau-forecasts.html'&gt;gains a similar 20%&lt;/a&gt; each year. As the two most populous nations in the world, their rapid growth rates spike global production demand. The impact is huge. Couple this with generally low supply and it&amp;#8217;s clear why we&amp;#8217;ve been shelling out more at the checkout line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, one local store put up this little apology:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/misc/demanding-price.jpg' alt='Supermarket Apology' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, one positive note: this month Brazil reported a &lt;em&gt;reduction&lt;/em&gt; to biennial crop variations. Arabica beans follow a yearly low-yield/high-yield cycle. This decreased variation may be a result of improved agriculture. Might this combat the established two-year price floor on coffee futures? Too early to speculate, but it&amp;#8217;s interesting nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/market">market</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/price">price</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasting Notes - Pachamama - Santa Teresa, Peru</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-pachamama-peru.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed Feb 23 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-pachamama-peru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This review is difficult to write. Difficult not only because I have to be harsh, but also because I feel like I&amp;#8217;ve failed. I attempt to find a redeeming or commendable quality in just about every brew I try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t find anything to like about &lt;a href='http://www.pachamama.coop/detail.cfm?id=3930'&gt;Pachamama&amp;#8217;s Peruvian offering&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s just bad coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It lacks aroma. The mouthfeel is indistinguishable from tepid water. The acidity is off the chart. Its flavor is simple and singular; but unfortunately that flavor is dirt. I&amp;#8217;m not exaggerating, it tastes like dirt. Or, more specifically, dirt-laden coffee bean skins (chaff).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My typical review process is to brew and drink several cups over a few days, making notes each time. When I sit down to write the review, I&amp;#8217;ll brew up another cup and go over my previous notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m sitting here drinking my third cup of this monstrosity and my opinion hasn&amp;#8217;t changed. The nuance that usually reveals itself after repeated tastings is completely absent. I hate this bean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things I do for you people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/review">review</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/tasting-notes">tasting-notes</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/pachamama">pachamama</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/0-stars">0-stars</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasting Notes - Equal Exchange's Organic Midnight Sun</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-equal-exchange-organic-midnight-sun.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat Jan 22 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-equal-exchange-organic-midnight-sun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I Grabbed this &lt;a href='http://shop.equalexchange.com/ProductInfo.aspx?productid=10032'&gt;dark roast from Equal Exchange&lt;/a&gt; at the local co-op on sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun/equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun_-beans.jpg' alt='Equal Exchange - Organic Midnight Sun - Beans' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at how oily these suckers are! They&amp;#8217;re practically dripping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brewed in my small Chemex, the finished product was decent, but lacking; so I moved on to the AeroPress. Using two tablespoons of beans–finely ground–produced a very tasty cup!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun/equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun_-crema.jpg' alt='Equal Exchange - Organic Midnight Sun - Crema' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aroma is thick with syrup, almost malty. The flavor is quite rich with absolutely no notes of fruit and a very heavy, bold coffee flavor. Its taste is rather simple. It feels heavy in the mouth with very low acidity. The crema is creamy and rich with oil. As I often experience–quite enjoyably–with dark roasts there is a subtle coconut aftertaste mixed with dark chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Midnight Sun is drinkable despite its fairly modest complexity. It lingers on the tongue &lt;em&gt;slighty&lt;/em&gt; too long and tastes exclusively of coffee. The flavor lacks nuance, as is common with the darkest roasts, but this is disappointing only if you&amp;#8217;re expecting a diverse flavor profile. This roast won&amp;#8217;t grab everyone, but those who enjoy their drink bold will find something to like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun/equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun_-cup.jpg' alt='Equal Exchange - Organic Midnight Sun - Finished Cup' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Verdict&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; if you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; like dark roasts. 2 Stars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/review">review</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/tasting-notes">tasting-notes</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/equal-exchange">equal-exchange</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/dark-roast">dark-roast</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/2-stars">2-stars</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brushing a Duck's Teeth</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/brushing-a-ducks-teeth.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue Jan 18 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/brushing-a-ducks-teeth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always been lousy at introductions, so I&amp;#8217;ll get straight to the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, coffee and I – we sort of have a &amp;#8216;thing.&amp;#8217; I confess. Well, it&amp;#8217;s really more of a lusty infatuation. I figure if we&amp;#8217;re going to keep spending this much time together, I should probably learn a thing or two about her. You know, so we have something to talk about &lt;em&gt;above&lt;/em&gt; the sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll use this space to collect tasting notes and make snarky comments on the generally snobby coffee community. I won&amp;#8217;t, however, get into pedantic discussions over the precise pressure to pull a proper shot of espresso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I probably will keep up the alliteration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/introduction">introduction</category>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>