<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Coffee Comrade</title>
    <link>http://coffeecomrade.com</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <webMaster>bryanwarren@gmail.com (Bryan Matthew Warren)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>2011-03-10T17:26:18-05:00</pubDate>
    <copyright>Copyright 2011</copyright>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <description>Coffee reviews, tasting notes and commentary</description>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simmer Your Steamer Wand</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/simmer-your-steamer-wand.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri Mar 04 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/simmer-your-steamer-wand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m disturbed by the aggressive elitism of some coffee shops. I can dig an attitude or edginess; it can often set your shop apart and dictate the type of clientele you draw. But when your ethos becomes a thinly-veiled ego stroke, it&amp;#8217;s time to chill down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I visited a shop that billed itself as an &amp;#8220;espresso bar&amp;#8221; rather than a coffee shop. Again, I can dig that. Ostensibly, it tells me that I can expect a higher level of service than a clerk filling my cup from an airpot&lt;sup id='fnref:1'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:1' rel='footnote'&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. A friend had warned me that the owner was &amp;#8221;&lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; into his coffee,&amp;#8221; but that only piqued my curiosity. I ordered my standard Americano (oddly, no option for a double).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll admit it was an expertly prepared Americano. I&amp;#8217;ve lost count of the shops I&amp;#8217;ve visited that flub up the order of preparation for a relatively straightforward drink. This shop had it down pat, using a vintage La Marzocca to pull a perfect shot. And it tasted pretty good to boot. But it wasn&amp;#8217;t the &lt;em&gt;best tasting&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;#8217;ve had, despite the flawless preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked the barista whose beans they were using. His response? &amp;#8220;Just local organic beans.&amp;#8221; Red flag. Why be so tight lipped about your product? If anything, you should be proud of your choice of roast, especially in an area with an abundance of fantastic and community-oriented roasters. No need to act like Mr. Slurm cornered you in an alley, there, Charlie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got home, I pulled up the espresso bar&amp;#8217;s website. In a contrived question/answer section, the owner&amp;#8217;s position on flavored coffee drinks is to suggest the gas station down the road. While possibly funny, the response mirrored the general atmosphere of his shop. You are the consumer, I am the expert. No thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s really no place for snobbery. Sure, I cringe at the thought of mixing a great shot of espresso with a bunch of industrial flavorings. You don&amp;#8217;t, however, need to cast stones at those who don&amp;#8217;t know the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take for example another local shop. A few months ago, I was waiting at the register when a woman stepped up with a puzzled look on her face. She stared down into her tall paper cup contemplating what she might be looking at. The barista offered his assistance and the woman said she&amp;#8217;d ordered a machiatto but only received a small cup of &amp;#8220;something&amp;#8221; when she expected a full glass of mostly milk. Instead of chastising the woman for her ignorance to the terminology, the barista asked if she usually ordered machiattos from Starbucks and proceeded to explain the difference between their variation on a latte machiatto and a true caffè machiatto. He did this while remaking her drink the way she expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exchange left the customer seemingly happy and definitely more educated. Instead of a scolding, she walked away with a drink for which she knew the proper name and a more educated view of coffee drinks. She&amp;#8217;ll probably return to the shop, or at least won&amp;#8217;t write them off as pompous and condescending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loving your craft is great. When that love turns into a fetish indulging superiority complex, you&amp;#8217;re being counterproductive. No one likes to feel patronized and that sort of stiff necked behavior only drives customers out of the specialty shops and back to the prosaic national chains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least they can expect a drink there rather than a glare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='footnotes'&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id='fn:1'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aside, one of the best cups of coffee I&amp;#8217;ve ever had came from an airpot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='#fnref:1' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/commentary">commentary</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/culture">culture</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/shops">shops</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasting Notes - Dynamite Roasting - Black Powder Espresso Blend</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-dynamite-roasting-black-powder-espresso-blend.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue Mar 01 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-dynamite-roasting-black-powder-espresso-blend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.dynamiteroasting.com/'&gt;Dynamite Roasting&lt;/a&gt; is a local organic roaster in Black Mountain, NC. I&amp;#8217;ve &lt;a href='http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-dynamite-roasting-sumatra-mandheling.html'&gt;written before about their Sumatra Mandheling&lt;/a&gt; roast–one of my favorite coffees. I recently had the chance to visit their coffee bar and pick up their &lt;a href='http://www.dynamiteroasting.com/onlinestore.html'&gt;Black Powder Espresso Blend&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-dynamite_-black-powder/dynamite-black-powder-bag.jpg' alt='Dynamite Roasting - Black Powder Espresso Blend' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dark roast has an intense coffee aroma with tones of cream and nut oil. As an espresso blend, the beans are roasted well into the second crack but don&amp;#8217;t suffer the common &amp;#8220;roasted-to-hell&amp;#8221; trait of many similar blends. There&amp;#8217;s no musky or meaty&lt;sup id='fnref:1'&gt;&lt;a href='#fn:1' rel='footnote'&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; burnt smell here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-dynamite_-black-powder/dynamite-black-powder-beans.jpg' alt='Dynamite Roasting - Black Powder Espresso Blend - Beans' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flavor profile is extremely complex. Most pronounced is a smack of dark cocoa trailed by mild berry fruit notes and a hint of nut. The flavor is quite strong and rather dark, but remains balanced with no overwhelming elements. The finished cup has great body and a very smooth finish with fairly low acidity. Its flavor lingers and has a bit of bite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there&amp;#8217;s the gorgeous copper crema. Heaps of the stuff. It&amp;#8217;s like pouring a pint of Guinness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-dynamite_-black-powder/dynamite-black-powder-crema.jpg' alt='Dynamite Roasting - Black Powder Espresso Blend - Crema' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While at Dynamite&amp;#8217;s bar, I sampled a straight double shot and a double Americano. On a return trip, I tried another double Americano, but iced. Since then, I&amp;#8217;ve been enjoying double Americanos at home from my AeroPress. This blend holds up. I can see it working well in any blended coffee drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dynamite Roasting&amp;#8217;s Black Powder Espresso is–quite possibly–the best &lt;em&gt;espresso&lt;/em&gt; blend I&amp;#8217;ve ever had. It&amp;#8217;s complex but balanced; both subtle and bold. As good as it is, I wouldn&amp;#8217;t want it every day since it&amp;#8217;s so bold. A solid 4 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='footnotes'&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id='fn:1'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, over-roasted beans smell like meat. Baconesque, but in a bad way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='#fnref:1' rev='footnote'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/review">review</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/tasting-notes">tasting-notes</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/espresso">espresso</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/dynamite">dynamite</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/4-stars">4-stars</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasting Notes - Equal Exchange - Organic Love Buzz</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-equal-exchange-organic-love-buzz.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon Feb 28 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-equal-exchange-organic-love-buzz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why do roasters produce &amp;#8220;Vanlentine&amp;#8217;s Day&amp;#8221; blends? Not that I&amp;#8217;m complaining; the more roasts the better. I suppose the idea of blending beans is supposed to evoke images of the blending of souls. Whatever works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-equal-exchange_-organic-love-buzz/equal-exchange-organic-love-buzz-beans.jpg' alt='Equal Exchange - Organic Love Buzz - Beans' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, the love-themed roasts on shelves for the past month caught my eye, in particular &lt;a href='http://www.equalexchange.coop/coffee-blends#OLB'&gt;Equal Exchange&amp;#8217;s Organic Love Buzz&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s a &amp;#8220;post-roast&amp;#8221; blend, meaning the beans are mixed after they&amp;#8217;ve been fully roasted. This is a great blending method, especially for a darker roast. Mixing the beans before cooking tends to homogenize the flavor. Keeping them separate as they roast allows for a more interesting and defined taste in the finished product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-equal-exchange_-organic-love-buzz/equal-exchange-organic-love-buzz-grounds.jpg' alt='Equal Exchange - Organic Love Buzz - Grounds' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blend has a distinctly pleasant and lightly sweet aroma more reminiscent of fruit than caramelized sugars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a finished cup, Love Buzz is both dark and creamy with a prominent malty hook. The flavor has a rich and deeply fruity foundation. Its profile is decently complex, and the faint astringency lends a cheerful note to its middle-of-the-road acidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brew is a little thin in the mouth, and its aftertaste is fleeting. As the cup cools down, the flavor intensifies. This inspired me to try the roast cold-brewed. It&amp;#8217;s a solid drink prepared as an iced Americano, which speaks to its diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What gets me about this roast is how I keep coming back. Granted, my local co-op ran a month-long sale on the blend for only $8.50 a pound. I&amp;#8217;ve gone through two pounds of the stuff so far. Despite the bargain price tag, this is a commendable blend that brews into a great, drinkable cup. 4 stars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/commentary">commentary</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/culture">culture</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/shops">shops</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demanding Price</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/demanding-price.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat Feb 26 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/demanding-price/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The International Coffee Organization&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href='http://www.ico.org/news/cmr-0111-e.pdf'&gt;latest monthly report (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; is out and the news is still somewhat grim. They cite continued weather woes as the chief cause of low crop yields. Green coffee prices haven&amp;#8217;t been so high in over 15 years, and we&amp;#8217;ve seen a 55% increase in the past twelve months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chinese demand for coffee &lt;a href='http://www.bloomberg.com/apps/news?pid=newsarchive&amp;amp;sid=aq3ewkyLbKuc'&gt;grows about 20% annually&lt;/a&gt;, and India&amp;#8217;s market &lt;a href='http://www.businessweek.com/news/2010-04-28/coffee-demand-in-india-to-drive-imports-board-s-rau-forecasts.html'&gt;gains a similar 20%&lt;/a&gt; each year. As the two most populous nations in the world, their rapid growth rates spike global production demand. The impact is huge. Couple this with generally low supply and it&amp;#8217;s clear why we&amp;#8217;ve been shelling out more at the checkout line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, one local store put up this little apology:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/misc/demanding-price.jpg' alt='Supermarket Apology' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, one positive note: this month Brazil reported a &lt;em&gt;reduction&lt;/em&gt; to biennial crop variations. Arabica beans follow a yearly low-yield/high-yield cycle. This decreased variation may be a result of improved agriculture. Might this combat the established two-year price floor on coffee futures? Too early to speculate, but it&amp;#8217;s interesting nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/market">market</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/price">price</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasting Notes - Pachamama - Santa Teresa, Peru</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-pachamama-peru.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed Feb 23 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-pachamama-peru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This review is difficult to write. Difficult not only because I have to be harsh, but also because I feel like I&amp;#8217;ve failed. I attempt to find a redeeming or commendable quality in just about every brew I try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t find anything to like about &lt;a href='http://www.pachamama.coop/detail.cfm?id=3930'&gt;Pachamama&amp;#8217;s Peruvian offering&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s just bad coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It lacks aroma. The mouthfeel is indistinguishable from tepid water. The acidity is off the chart. Its flavor is simple and singular; but unfortunately that flavor is dirt. I&amp;#8217;m not exaggerating, it tastes like dirt. Or, more specifically, dirt-laden coffee bean skins (chaff).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My typical review process is to brew and drink several cups over a few days, making notes each time. When I sit down to write the review, I&amp;#8217;ll brew up another cup and go over my previous notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m sitting here drinking my third cup of this monstrosity and my opinion hasn&amp;#8217;t changed. The nuance that usually reveals itself after repeated tastings is completely absent. I hate this bean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things I do for you people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/review">review</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/tasting-notes">tasting-notes</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/pachamama">pachamama</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/0-stars">0-stars</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasting Notes - Dynamite Roasting - Sumatra Mandheling</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-dynamite-roasting-sumatra-mandheling.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed Jan 26 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-dynamite-roasting-sumatra-mandheling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.dynamiteroasting.com/'&gt;Dynamite Roasting&lt;/a&gt; cooks up beans in Black Mountain, NC. The organic roaster offers a wide variety of both blends and single-origin roasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-dynamite_-sumatra-mandheling/tasting_-dynamite_-sumatra-mandheling_-beans.jpg' alt='Dynamite Roasting - Sumatra Mandheling - Beans' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mandailing'&gt;Mandheling&lt;/a&gt; beans are a medium roast that edge slightly toward dark. The aroma is deep and decidedly &amp;#8220;brown&amp;#8221; with strong punches of salt and earth. Yeah, &amp;#8220;earth.&amp;#8221; In a good way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-dynamite_-sumatra-mandheling/tasting_-dynamite_-sumatra-mandheling_-grounds.jpg' alt='Dynamite Roasting - Sumatra Mandheling - Grounds' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nut flavor is pervasive, held up by subtle wood and oil textures. There&amp;#8217;s a light hint of dark fruit–maybe cherry or pomegranate. The brew feels very thin and almost weightless. While this may seem like a reflection of poor body, the finished cup has an excellent build that allows the light weight to shine through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could drink this stuff all day. The aftertaste is just right; it doesn&amp;#8217;t overstay its welcome. Surprisingly, the cup smells precisely as delicious as the grounds. This almost never happens. It&amp;#8217;s an honest roast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='verdict'&gt;Verdict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dynamite Roasting&amp;#8217;s &lt;strong&gt;Sumatra Mandheling&lt;/strong&gt; is a real workhorse. It&amp;#8217;s a general-purpose roast that works just as well in a drip pot as in espresso drinks. Several local joints keep this in their air pots. It&amp;#8217;s good that way, but loses a lot of complexity. Brewed any other way, this roast is exceedingly excellent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My review may not have reflected this, but I&amp;#8217;m trying to show a bit of restraint. Dynamite&amp;#8217;s Indonesian offering is my favorite coffee. No hyperbole. 5 Stars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/review">review</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/tasting-notes">tasting-notes</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/dynamite">dynamite</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/medium-roast">medium-roast</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/5-stars">5-stars</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasting Notes - Equal Exchange's Organic Midnight Sun</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-equal-exchange-organic-midnight-sun.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat Jan 22 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-equal-exchange-organic-midnight-sun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I Grabbed this &lt;a href='http://shop.equalexchange.com/ProductInfo.aspx?productid=10032'&gt;dark roast from Equal Exchange&lt;/a&gt; at the local co-op on sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun/equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun_-beans.jpg' alt='Equal Exchange - Organic Midnight Sun - Beans' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at how oily these suckers are! They&amp;#8217;re practically dripping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brewed in my small Chemex, the finished product was decent, but lacking; so I moved on to the AeroPress. Using two tablespoons of beans–finely ground–produced a very tasty cup!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun/equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun_-crema.jpg' alt='Equal Exchange - Organic Midnight Sun - Crema' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aroma is thick with syrup, almost malty. The flavor is quite rich with absolutely no notes of fruit and a very heavy, bold coffee flavor. Its taste is rather simple. It feels heavy in the mouth with very low acidity. The crema is creamy and rich with oil. As I often experience–quite enjoyably–with dark roasts there is a subtle coconut aftertaste mixed with dark chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Midnight Sun is drinkable despite its fairly modest complexity. It lingers on the tongue &lt;em&gt;slighty&lt;/em&gt; too long and tastes exclusively of coffee. The flavor lacks nuance, as is common with the darkest roasts, but this is disappointing only if you&amp;#8217;re expecting a diverse flavor profile. This roast won&amp;#8217;t grab everyone, but those who enjoy their drink bold will find something to like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun/equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun_-cup.jpg' alt='Equal Exchange - Organic Midnight Sun - Finished Cup' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='verdict'&gt;Verdict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommended &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; if you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; like dark roasts. 2 Stars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/review">review</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/tasting-notes">tasting-notes</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/equal-exchange">equal-exchange</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/dark-roast">dark-roast</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/2-stars">2-stars</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brushing a Duck's Teeth</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/brushing-a-ducks-teeth.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue Jan 18 00:00:00 -0500 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/brushing-a-ducks-teeth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always been lousy at introductions, so I&amp;#8217;ll get straight to the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, coffee and I – we sort of have a &amp;#8216;thing.&amp;#8217; I confess. Well, it&amp;#8217;s really more of a lusty infatuation. I figure if we&amp;#8217;re going to keep spending this much time together, I should probably learn a thing or two about her. You know, so we have something to talk about &lt;em&gt;above&lt;/em&gt; the sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll use this space to collect tasting notes and make snarky comments on the generally snobby coffee community. I won&amp;#8217;t, however, get into pedantic discussions over the precise pressure to pull a proper shot of espresso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I probably will keep up the alliteration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/introduction">introduction</category>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>